<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Future on Entropiex</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/categories/future/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Future on Entropiex</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Entropiex</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/categories/future/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Embedded Systems Engineering</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/embedded-systems-engineering/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/embedded-systems-engineering/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/embedded-systems-engineering/Embedded%20Systems%20Engineering%20Roadmap.png" alt="Featured image of post Embedded Systems Engineering" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hardware is hard? Then go for it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In early 2025, I did some research about future opportunities, and seems like AI can replace most single-ability people in a not far future. The block chain technology and models led by transformers are now a large market and are still expanding. Unfortunately, just like the Internet boom, the best time has passed, so I need to find something still useful in future, and I realized that the combination of hardware and software that embedded development provide is one of the strongest ability I have seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until AI can directly control the real world, micro-quantum computers appear, and brain-computer interfaces have the ability to inherit memory, embedded development will always exist - because all current electronic industry are built on the basis of embedded development. The decline of embedded means the rise of a new generation of computers with non-von Neumann architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computer Science alone is too boring for me. For this reason, in 2025 I decided to start learning everything about embedded development. This will be another new starting point after I acquire the ability to design for additive manufacturing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wish me luck.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
