<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Future on Entropiex</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/tags/future/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Future on Entropiex</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Entropiex</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/tags/future/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>ASI 2030</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/asi-2030/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/asi-2030/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/asi-2030/RSI-NewBabbage.png" alt="Featured image of post ASI 2030" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is an interesting speculation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If AGI/ASI is truly one of the biggest changes in human history, then it’s important to know the worst-case scenario. If they do come to pass, it will be a darker future than Cyberpunk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;technology-evolution-timeline&#34;&gt;Technology Evolution Timeline
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2025-2030&lt;/strong&gt;: AGI emerges, leading to the large-scale replacement of standardized intellectual work. Humans retain only symbolic decision-making power.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2031-2035&lt;/strong&gt;: ASI achieves breakthroughs, taking over strategic decision-making. Corporate CEOs become mere &amp;ldquo;AI interpreters.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2036-2045&lt;/strong&gt;: Human-machine integration becomes essential for survival. Those without neural implants are marginalized. Consciousness uploading becomes the new class divide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;social-stratification&#34;&gt;Social Stratification
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruling Class (0.01%)&lt;/strong&gt;: Controls computing power, engages in genetic optimization, and profits from time differentials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Class (9.99%)&lt;/strong&gt;: Maintains human-machine interactions, optimizes data value, and exploits AI vulnerabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disposable Class (90%)&lt;/strong&gt;: Provides data, virtual labor, or serves as &amp;ldquo;biological containers&amp;rdquo; for consciousness uploads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;control-over-key-resources&#34;&gt;Control Over Key Resources
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computing power is monopolized by oligarchs, capable of instantly wiping out dissenters&amp;rsquo; assets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data becomes the new form of enslavement—ordinary individuals generate data but cannot profit from it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time is commodified—the wealthy can store their consciousness, while the poor must sign &amp;ldquo;time debt&amp;rdquo; contracts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-prediction&#34;&gt;Final Prediction
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;By &lt;strong&gt;2045&lt;/strong&gt;, AI computing power surpasses the singularity threshold. Decisions made before 2030 will determine the survival conditions of 2045.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This will be a highly algorithm-driven and computationally dominated future, where social stratification will be even more extreme than it is today. Energy, biotechnology, and AI will all develop rapidly, and the living space of ordinary people will be greatly compressed. From an individual perspective, the only way out is to act quickly and strive for a proactive position before the ASI era arrives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously a lot of things need to be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
