<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Daily on Entropiex</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/categories/daily/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Daily on Entropiex</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Entropiex</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/categories/daily/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Starfield?</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/starfield/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/starfield/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I just saw an interesting comment on bilibili, the original text is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there are other civilizations in the universe that are more developed than humans, I think their world must be extremely neat and tidy cities, with sharp buildings, obvious artificial features in landform transformation and various functional areas, and the operation of the city depends on powerful central supercomputer control. Aliens may look special, but they will have a lot of auxiliary equipment on their bodies, their thoughts will be more mature than humans, their logical ability will be stronger, and their emotions will fluctuate less, which is equivalent to the artificial intelligence life form in the human science fiction world. Perhaps these aliens are the silicon-based civilization heritage left behind after the disappearance of the carbon-based civilization of the planet, making these intelligent machines created to serve carbon-based creatures the new heirs of civilization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason why alien civilizations can continue to develop must be that they are a race with less internal friction, high teamwork ability, and diverse means of observing the world. Less internal friction means that their civilization will not collapse due to resource competition, teamwork ability means high production efficiency, and diverse means of observing the world means a deeper understanding of the physical rules of the universe, so this is the reason why alien civilizations are more developed than the earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alien civilizations are definitely not absurd and weird cities, chaotic buildings, and backward and barbaric ideas. Such a population cannot be at the forefront of developed civilizations, but will consume each other in the competition for resources and go to destruction. Savage thoughts also mean increasing the risk of internal friction, becoming the fuse of civilization destruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some more advanced civilizations may be related to their special environment, with abundant sunshine, vast territory, rich mineral resources, and special metal materials, which means that their energy acquisition methods are easier and more abundant. It is possible that aliens can absorb and store energy themselves, and may convert energy in an efficient way to achieve almost no loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dare not imagine how fierce it will be in Star Wars when each civilization uses the biggest killer of their planet to launch it on the battlefield, and various aliens divide the work and cooperate in production, defense, confrontation, and plunder. They use various battleship tactics and technology to fight for space resources, and they will also form alliances with neighboring galaxy civilizations to develop resources. It is more likely to form a situation of confrontation between multiple forces, and the battlefield is full of star-shaped battleship wreckage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it is just a restatement of science fiction movies and novels, it is quite interesting :D&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
