<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Daily on Entropiex</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/categories/daily/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Daily on Entropiex</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Entropiex</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/categories/daily/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Prior Probability of Life</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/prior-probability-of-life/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/prior-probability-of-life/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is the last day of September. Looking back, this month has passed very quickly and I have learned a lot. The most important thing is to establish the White Room system, and thinking about the life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Bayesian theory, life should also consist of prior probability and posterior probability. Being alive and healthy constitutes the prior probability, while thoughts and actions constitute the posterior probability. When all conditions are met, it is the road to victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the coming month, I decided to finish my high school physics content and improve my English, everything will be checked on my birthday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy October!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>New things Todo</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/new-things-todo/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/new-things-todo/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;These are things to do next few days:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;0-create-review-sheet-for-all-school-courses&#34;&gt;0. Create review sheet for all school courses
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;h5 id=&#34;1-update-time-flip-210&#34;&gt;1. Update Time Flip 2.1.0
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;h5 id=&#34;2-start-developing-time-slice-t-slice&#34;&gt;2. Start developing Time Slice (T-Slice)
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;h5 id=&#34;3-start-developing-hugo-poster-for-obsidian&#34;&gt;3. Start developing Hugo Poster for Obsidian
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;h5 id=&#34;4-start-developing-hugo-poster-for-obsidian&#34;&gt;4. Start developing Hugo Poster for Obsidian
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;h5 id=&#34;5-start-ap-courses&#34;&gt;5. Start AP courses
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;h5 id=&#34;6-restart-meditation&#34;&gt;6. Restart Meditation
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hopefully they could be done perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Time Slice, The beginning of everything</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/time-slice-the-beginning-of-everything/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/time-slice-the-beginning-of-everything/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;一些完美主义和远视主义的思索&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;生活在静好的岁月里，没有人再会去冒险了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我意识到有时我们必须有一份承诺；
让你不要在任何时候退却，放弃，无所适从；
让它像激光一样拨开谜语，指引方向；
永远无法得到过去的时间，因为历史被推着前进。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;光阴轮转，但等到意识到轮转之时便是为之已晚。
落叶归根，但南方的常青树并不会因为秋季落叶。
世界的不完美是留给完美主义者最好的馈赠；
陷入轮回之时，是承诺达成之日。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这是一篇故事，从今天开始写的故事；
它将解释我的一切，在哪以及为什么这么做：
让一切变得有趣，欢乐，充满意义。
让回忆成为快乐的事，让体验成为唯一的佐证。
当目标是极致的时候，你不得不将一切推向更高。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这是一个四维空间，我是生活在三位切片上的人类。
无论对于文明还是个体，只有从高维思考才能解决那些无法想象，甚至无法提出的问题——但是它们客观存在，造成了不完美。
这是时间切片。
三维世界里可以轻易将立方体展开为1个面的平坦白纸，反之亦然；
三维世界里可以轻易创造莫比乌斯带，将两个完全隔离的二位世界拼接。
在四位世界里，三维的一切相形见绌，因此只要控制时间维度，所有问题都将迎刃而解，原本困难的问题变得轻而易举。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;时间被设置成单向的，红移不会停止，熵增不会结束。
锁死流向的时间大大减少了操作空间，但是它仅仅被锁死了方向，因此通过改变流速和效率依然可以一定上程度进行弥补。
这是时间切片，一种全新的时间管理方式：
它将真正描述这个四维空间。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;让回忆成为享受，而不是遗憾。
唯一的承诺，贯穿整个四维空间：
一定要改变世界，让它变得更好。
财富，知识，能力，让人类更加伟大。
从现在开始，构建属于自己的White Room。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Starfield?</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/starfield/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/starfield/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I just saw an interesting comment on bilibili, the original text is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there are other civilizations in the universe that are more developed than humans, I think their world must be extremely neat and tidy cities, with sharp buildings, obvious artificial features in landform transformation and various functional areas, and the operation of the city depends on powerful central supercomputer control. Aliens may look special, but they will have a lot of auxiliary equipment on their bodies, their thoughts will be more mature than humans, their logical ability will be stronger, and their emotions will fluctuate less, which is equivalent to the artificial intelligence life form in the human science fiction world. Perhaps these aliens are the silicon-based civilization heritage left behind after the disappearance of the carbon-based civilization of the planet, making these intelligent machines created to serve carbon-based creatures the new heirs of civilization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason why alien civilizations can continue to develop must be that they are a race with less internal friction, high teamwork ability, and diverse means of observing the world. Less internal friction means that their civilization will not collapse due to resource competition, teamwork ability means high production efficiency, and diverse means of observing the world means a deeper understanding of the physical rules of the universe, so this is the reason why alien civilizations are more developed than the earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alien civilizations are definitely not absurd and weird cities, chaotic buildings, and backward and barbaric ideas. Such a population cannot be at the forefront of developed civilizations, but will consume each other in the competition for resources and go to destruction. Savage thoughts also mean increasing the risk of internal friction, becoming the fuse of civilization destruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some more advanced civilizations may be related to their special environment, with abundant sunshine, vast territory, rich mineral resources, and special metal materials, which means that their energy acquisition methods are easier and more abundant. It is possible that aliens can absorb and store energy themselves, and may convert energy in an efficient way to achieve almost no loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dare not imagine how fierce it will be in Star Wars when each civilization uses the biggest killer of their planet to launch it on the battlefield, and various aliens divide the work and cooperate in production, defense, confrontation, and plunder. They use various battleship tactics and technology to fight for space resources, and they will also form alliances with neighboring galaxy civilizations to develop resources. It is more likely to form a situation of confrontation between multiple forces, and the battlefield is full of star-shaped battleship wreckage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it is just a restatement of science fiction movies and novels, it is quite interesting :D&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
