<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Many-Worlds Interpretation on Entropiex</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/categories/many-worlds-interpretation/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Many-Worlds Interpretation on Entropiex</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Entropiex</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/categories/many-worlds-interpretation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Time Travel in MWI</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/time-travel-in-mwi/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/time-travel-in-mwi/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/time-travel-in-mwi/TVL.png" alt="Featured image of post Time Travel in MWI" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In classical conceptions of time travel, particularly within a single-timeline universe, the grandfather paradox poses a serious logical problem: if a person travels back in time and prevents their grandfather from having children, how could the time traveler have been born to commit the act in the first place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can see that the grandfather paradox assumes two premises:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We live in a shared reality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The reality of the past and the future is the same, and all events are caused by cause and effect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, these two assumptions are not correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;time-travel-under-mwi&#34;&gt;Time Travel Under MWI
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Many-Worlds Interpretation (MWI)&lt;/strong&gt; of quantum mechanics offers a fundamentally different framework that avoids such paradoxes altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MWI posits that every quantum event with multiple possible outcomes causes the universe to split into multiple, non-interacting branches, each representing a different outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional MWI theory holds that the universe does not have a single timeline, but an infinite &amp;ldquo;tree&amp;rdquo; composed of divergent world lines. In fact, it is more likely that all the divergent world lines themselves have always existed and formed a &amp;ldquo;grid&amp;rdquo; in which consciousness constantly shuttles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If time travel is possible in such a framework, then the traveler is not moving backwards along a single timeline. We know that the traveler is actually constantly traveling between worldlines, so their arrival in the &amp;ldquo;past&amp;rdquo; will result in the creation or intersection of a new worldline, a parallel branch that diverges from the point of arrival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this branching structure, meeting a version of your past self is plausible. However, the &amp;ldquo;you&amp;rdquo; that exists in that past is not the exact same entity that became the future traveler. Rather, it is a copy on a parallel worldline. The moment you travel back, you create or join a branch where both versions of you co-exist, and their timelines may continue independently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we also know that shadow people do not have a dominant consciousness, which means you will meet your shadow people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-the-grandfather-paradox-doesnt-occur&#34;&gt;Why the Grandfather Paradox Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Occur
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because of this branching, any actions taken in the &amp;ldquo;past&amp;rdquo; do not overwrite the traveler&amp;rsquo;s origin timeline. If you were to stop your grandfather from having children in that new branch, it would not affect the original branch from which you came. Instead, it would only change the course of history in that particular parallel world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this way, causality is preserved within each branch, and no contradictions arise. The original sequence of events that led to your birth remains intact in your original worldline, even if you prevent it in another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, your shadow copy has no logical connection with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In our MWI framework, there is only one dominant consciousness, so even if the dominant consciousness returns to the world lines it has been to, it will only encounter its own &amp;ldquo;shadow man&amp;rdquo;. This will not cause the dominant consciousness to suddenly visit itself in its memory, because the dominant consciousness returns to that world line after it has experienced that world line. The dominant consciousness&amp;rsquo;s memory will not change because it does not have the experience of the &amp;ldquo;shadow man&amp;rdquo; on the world line it returned to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, in theory, there is nothing wrong with killing your grandfather. Furthermore, if your grandfather has passed away, then you have not actually killed anyone, because at this time all &amp;ldquo;grandfathers&amp;rdquo; are just empty shells, and the dominant consciousness has left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In MWI, time travel is as easy as moving around in the three-dimensional world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Shadow People in MWI</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/shadow-people-in-mwi/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/shadow-people-in-mwi/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/shadow-people-in-mwi/SP04.png" alt="Featured image of post Shadow People in MWI" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;occupancy&#34;&gt;Occupancy
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on what was discussed previously, 99.99999% of world-lines are empty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that most of the world lines that consciousness experiences are simply filled with other people, animals, and things that have no consciousness. These people and animals are called &amp;ldquo;shadows&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;shadow people&amp;rdquo; because while they appear to move and think, they have no consciousness. They are projections of consciousness, and their main consciousness is somewhere else. They are the &amp;ldquo;what ifs&amp;rdquo; of the action and the landscape that your consciousness interacts with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To visualize:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/shadow-people-in-mwi/SP01.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1481&#34;
	height=&#34;907&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/shadow-people-in-mwi/SP01_hu_18ffcc8e7dcfd54f.png 480w, https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/shadow-people-in-mwi/SP01_hu_e22984110c1af7.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;163&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;391px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this is a simplification. In reality, all the “shadow people” possess a consciousness. This explains why the thoughts of those around you affect your MWI navigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is some small percentage of a consciousness within every shadow entity. It’s just that the percentage is very tiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of the infinite lines of the world has consciousness running through it. Not just other people&amp;rsquo;s, but yours as well. It&amp;rsquo;s an almost insignificant amount. Your consciousness dominates all other consciousnesses in the world line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/shadow-people-in-mwi/SP02.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1470&#34;
	height=&#34;907&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/shadow-people-in-mwi/SP02_hu_360e0953916b7d77.png 480w, https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/shadow-people-in-mwi/SP02_hu_9cab663e63164cf0.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;162&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;388px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;some-explanations&#34;&gt;Some explanations
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In quantum physics, when two quanta meet, they become entangled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the realm outside of our reality; the one that contains all the near-infinite numbers of world-lines, there isn’t any time or space. It’s a region with no geometry. So everything can entangle in a quantum sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means there is no world-lines are independent. They are all connected to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is actually happening is that clusters of world-lines entangle with other clusters of world-lines. They do this when ever a consciousness is injected into a world-line template.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And all of this entanglement puts a little infinitesimal part of you, and those around you near you in what ever world-line that your consciousness happens to occupy at that moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are other factors at play. Injecting consciousness into a template does not mean that the entire infinite number of world lines are entangled. The effect will &amp;ldquo;fade out,&amp;rdquo; or diminish as the variance increases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will resemble something like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/shadow-people-in-mwi/SP03.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1380&#34;
	height=&#34;844&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/shadow-people-in-mwi/SP03_hu_652491b6f3f9b5d1.png 480w, https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/shadow-people-in-mwi/SP03_hu_4c0adba31f17793.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;163&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;392px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability of a consciousness to entangle with “close proximity” world-lines happens automatically. However, the ability for the entangled world-lines to entangle with other world-lines drops off as the degree of variance increases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider that this is happening for the billions upon billions of people that are entering and leaving our template surface. Each one is “making their marks”. All combine to provide some “foot print” of their present upon the template that you inhabit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;paradox&#34;&gt;Paradox
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assuming that everyone was 100% fully conscious in their bodies, and that the mind controlled our reality, our reality would probably become a very confusing, ever-changing mess of reality. Reality will also change as quickly and irrationally as dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/shadow-people-in-mwi/SP04.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1381&#34;
	height=&#34;862&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/shadow-people-in-mwi/SP04_hu_e638f18b6f141321.png 480w, https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/shadow-people-in-mwi/SP04_hu_ae5ad15e10589696.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;160&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;384px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a person&amp;rsquo;s consciousness is the dominant consciousness in the world line he lives in, it means that his thoughts are also the dominant thoughts in the world line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By controlling and directing thoughts, we can not only control our navigation, but our influence in the strong quantum entanglements of “near-by” (but untraveled) world-lines means that we have the potential to influence the trends and behaviors of the environment around us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>False Positives in MWI Navigation</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/false-positives-in-mwi-navigation/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/false-positives-in-mwi-navigation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One thing that can be pretty common in an intention campaign is the presence of “false positives”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;False positives are events or things that appear to match your verbal affirmations in substance, but have some glaring defect that makes them unusable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like ripples in a pond, a target object or situation can often create “ghost” or “echo” images. These items are not necessarily exactly what you are striving for. Though, it might (truthfully) be exactly what you are asking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if the navigation goal is &amp;ldquo;live in a brand new white room, eat whatever you want, close to the sea&amp;rdquo;, the target reality may be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You live in a brand new seaside prison, but the food there is good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You become a sailor and spend most of your time in a white cabin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it is not impossible to become a food tycoon and live in a seaside villa. But if no restrictions are set, the navigation direction will be towards the world line that is closest and most likely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A false positive is that you have become a food industry tycoon and live in a beachfront villa, but&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your villa is very humid, and the sea breeze causes water and salt to cover the walls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The shrinking food industry has caused you to be heavily in debt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no beach at the beach, and there are strong winds and huge waves all year round&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, the goal seems to have been achieved, but there are many problems. At this time, you need to make a course correction and make necessary adjustments to some details. The good news is that a false positive means that you have reached the world line cluster where the goal is located. By modifying the content of the Affirmation and spending more time, reality will get closer to the goal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The house is comfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The climate here is pleasant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The industry is booming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, time passes, and you get where you want to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Intention &amp; Navigation in MWI</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/intention-navigation-in-mwi/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/intention-navigation-in-mwi/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Released on April 1st, take it or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our thoughts control our reality. So if we want to live a “much improved” life, in whatever way we choose, we can manifest it. By understanding the way the universe works, the nature of consciousness, and the role thought has, you can pick and choose world-line destinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that you can direct your consciousness into the craziest, most complex worldline situations you can think of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only problem is that it takes time to manifest through world lines. The more outrageous the intention and desire, the farther the target world line is, and the more world boundaries your consciousness needs to pass through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to obtain the reality we want to inhabit, whatever that is, we need to develop a plan to make that happen. We need to navigate our consciousness through adjacent realities in order to eventually reach our final destination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;fundamentals&#34;&gt;Fundamentals
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;To be able to do this, we need:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A map, plan, or schedule of where we want to go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mastery of our thoughts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;planning---a-map&#34;&gt;Planning - A Map
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are always surprises when doing many things, no matter how big or small. The difficulty of a project is sometimes not well anticipated, and the same is true for world line navigation. Unless you are careful, the reality you live in may have all kinds of surprises. There, it is prudent for you to be careful and concerned when drawing the destination world line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the following scenario,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are currently in worldline reality &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo;. It is shown in green.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You eventually want to reach a new reality &amp;ldquo;B&amp;rdquo;. It is shown in gold.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are two paths marked. One is yellow and one is black.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/intention-navigation-in-mwi/WLT01.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;454&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/intention-navigation-in-mwi/WLT01_hu_d105dc7be7416060.png 480w, https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/intention-navigation-in-mwi/WLT01_hu_288dc5903388a789.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;225&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;541px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The yellow path is the most direct path. It will require fewer adjacent realities to pass through. The black path is the preferred path. It will take longer, because you will need to pass through more adjacent realities to get to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason that you want to take the black path over the yellow path is so that you can avoid those problematic realities. They are shown in grey. These realities will bring you turmoil and pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, when planning, there are a number of factors you need to be absolutely sure of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A destination lifestyle. Clear and easy to visualize. It must be very detailed. There must be no ambiguity in it what so ever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incorporate elements that will guarantee avoidance of problematic adjacent realities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mastery-of-our-thoughts&#34;&gt;Mastery of our thoughts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The key is to navigate the map we create above, which is often difficult to do because we need to control our thoughts, and modern life does not allow this. All the “fake news,” every ad you see, and all the thoughts of everyone around you influence your thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to see that if you want to make your planned end destination a reality, you&amp;rsquo;re going to need to shut down those bad thought streams. That means breaking some long-formed habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intention&#34;&gt; Intention
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prayer, directed thought, and focus are all great tools, as are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A visualization creation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a listing of what you want&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pray / visualize&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make a point to alert against bad realities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also note that the resulting reality will not be exact. It will be very close to what you want, but you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to specify exact people and exact locations, nor a very constructive level of detail. If you focus on your baseline wishes and desires, the rest will automatically fill in. Of course, it will get more and more accurate over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release&#34;&gt;Release
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contrary to what many people believe, this requires a period of forced inactivity. Resting, not doing anything, not even thinking about these goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, without this period of stagnation, nothing would happen. After you wind up the car, you can&amp;rsquo;t let it go until it moves forward. If you wind it up all the time, it will stay where it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The variables that will influence the timing of reality manifestation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How different and “far out” your goal is from your current reality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The thoughts and habits that you currently have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The thoughts of those around you, especially those of family members.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The discipline that you have in doing all of this to make your new world-line realized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-avoid-the-news&#34;&gt;Why avoid the news
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you start browsing MWI using personal intention, you’ll start to realize that all the news isn’t for you. It’s like wallpaper, it doesn’t affect your life in any way other than to scare you and make you cower in fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vocalize-it-loud&#34;&gt;Vocalize it loud
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why does this matter? And why do you need to say things out loud? Why not just think things instead?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As consciousness moves across world lines, it switches between wave and particle form. Your thoughts occur while you are in wave form, and through vocalization you can act while you are in particle form. Vocalization not only helps direct and focus the mind, but it is also the easiest action to take, which greatly speeds up goal achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are many other methods, using image boards, acting, pretending, and creating scenes. Physical action must be accompanied by directed thought to manifest, and vocalization satisfies this condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Law of Attraction Under MWI</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/law-of-attraction-under-mwi/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/law-of-attraction-under-mwi/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/law-of-attraction-under-mwi/Law-of-Attraction.png" alt="Featured image of post Law of Attraction Under MWI" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the MWI framework, every possible self you may become and every possible fate you may experience already &amp;ldquo;exists&amp;rdquo; in the universe, but they belong to different branching world lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, in the process of entering and exiting world lines, through the control of thoughts, we can select and strengthen the path weights of certain world lines, so that life experience tends towards those realities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every thought, emotion, intention, and belief is a &amp;ldquo;offset&amp;rdquo; operation on a certain world line. It all starts from the moment consciousness comes into the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Positive, confident, and determined thinking → makes you more likely to move towards a world with positive results;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fear, doubt, and self-denial → make you biased towards the branch with low probability and negative results;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also means that when you decide to start taking control of your thoughts, you first need to face the thoughts you have had for decades, which have shaped your reality today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since consciousness actually moves in and out of different world lines, we can see that thoughts not only choose/create reality, thoughts are reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because our thoughts determine what world-lines we enter into. So if we are thinking wonderful thoughts, and are calm, and direct our energy into wonderful things, our life would be wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if we surround ourselves with negative thoughts, manipulative news, and people. If we are reacting to events instead of manifesting them, or if we hold grudges and evil negative thoughts, then our world experiences will become progressively darker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thoughts create memories, and memories influence thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A poverty stricken beggar might yearn for a reality where he has a warm meal and a roof over his head from the rain. While a wealthy oligarch might yearn for forbidden activities, and serendipitous pursuits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This difference is due to their experiences, which are shaped by their memories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People discovered this phenomenon and named it the Law of Attraction. In fact, directed thoughts determine their reality.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What is MWI</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0008.png" alt="Featured image of post What is MWI" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction-to-the-many-worlds-interpretation-mwi&#34;&gt;Introduction to the Many-Worlds Interpretation (MWI)
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quantum mechanics emerged in the early 20th century to explain strange behaviors at the atomic and subatomic levels—such as electrons existing in multiple states at once or particles behaving like both waves and particles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathematically, quantum systems are described by a wavefunction (Ψ), which evolves deterministically over time according to the Schrödinger equation. This wavefunction contains all possible outcomes of a system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;copenhagen-interpretation-vs-mwi&#34;&gt;Copenhagen Interpretation vs. MWI
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the experiment we can know that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before measurement, particles exist in a &lt;strong&gt;superposition&lt;/strong&gt; of all possible states.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After measurement, we observe &lt;strong&gt;one definite outcome&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But where do the results come from?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Copenhagen Interpretation, developed primarily by Niels Bohr and Werner Heisenberg in the 1920s, was the first and most widely accepted explanation of this puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main idea includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The wavefunction represents &lt;strong&gt;our knowledge&lt;/strong&gt; of a system, not objective reality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a measurement is made, the wavefunction &lt;strong&gt;collapses&lt;/strong&gt; into a single outcome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior to observation, physical properties are &lt;strong&gt;undefined&lt;/strong&gt; or &amp;ldquo;potential.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it is clear that the Copenhagen interpretation suffers from a great deal of ambiguity: it has no clear way of defining “observation” or the observer, nor does it explain what actually exists before the observation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1957, physicist Hugh Everett III proposed the Many-Worlds Interpretation as a clean, deterministic alternative to Copenhagen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this theory:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The wavefunction &lt;strong&gt;never collapses&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All possible outcomes of quantum events &lt;strong&gt;actually happen&lt;/strong&gt;—in &lt;strong&gt;separate branches&lt;/strong&gt; of the universe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measurement causes &lt;strong&gt;decoherence&lt;/strong&gt;, not collapse: the world &amp;ldquo;splits&amp;rdquo; into multiple, non-interacting outcomes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A particle in superposition doesn’t choose one outcome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instead, the universe &lt;strong&gt;branches&lt;/strong&gt;, and each outcome occurs in its own “world.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further reasoning, any &amp;ldquo;forking&amp;rdquo; behavior may not exist, but the world line corresponding to each result itself always exists, and the observer moves between these worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;schrödingers-cat&#34;&gt;Schrödinger&amp;rsquo;s Cat
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Erwin Schrödinger proposed his famous thought experiment in 1935:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imagine a cat sealed in a box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inside, there is a radioactive atom with a 50% chance to decay in one hour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it decays, a Geiger counter triggers a hammer that breaks a vial of poison, killing the cat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it doesn’t decay, the cat lives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Copenhagen interpretation, the system remains in superposition (cat is dead and alive) until a measurement is made. At the moment of observation, the wavefunction collapses into one of the two possibilities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You see a &lt;strong&gt;live cat&lt;/strong&gt;, or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You see a &lt;strong&gt;dead cat&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only one outcome becomes real, and the other disappears. The act of observation causes reality to “choose.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MWI gives a different answer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cat is both dead and alive, but in different worlds.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In one &lt;strong&gt;branch&lt;/strong&gt; of the universe, the atom decays → poison is released → the cat dies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In another &lt;strong&gt;branch&lt;/strong&gt;, the atom does not decay → the poison is not released → the cat lives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two outcomes both happen, in separate branches of reality. There is no collapse but decoherence, which prevents the branches from interfering with each other:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you open the box, &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt; also become part of the superposition:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One version of you sees a &lt;strong&gt;dead cat&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another version sees a &lt;strong&gt;live cat&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;strong&gt;your&lt;/strong&gt; perspective as the observer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will experience &lt;strong&gt;only one outcome&lt;/strong&gt; (say, the live cat).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But &lt;strong&gt;another version of you&lt;/strong&gt;, equally real, experiences the &lt;strong&gt;other&lt;/strong&gt; outcome (dead cat).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You and your alternate self now live in &lt;strong&gt;separate, non-interacting worlds&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the above content, we can find that if MWI exists, the world will be &amp;ldquo;split&amp;rdquo; all the time, and the observer will move all the time, from one world to another. For the sake of distinction, the &amp;ldquo;world&amp;rdquo; will be called &amp;ldquo;world line&amp;rdquo; to more accurately describe the history and future of each world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;mwi-and-reality&#34;&gt;MWI and Reality
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The MWI is a large universe of possibilities. And each possibility is a frozen moment that our consciousness briefly visits. On top of this, our consciousness is constantly moving in and out of different realities. Since each reality is its own unique worldline, we can say that we are moving in and out of different worldlines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When consciousness enters an individual&amp;rsquo;s reality, this life begins a relatively fixed journey of life. Although we feel that we have free will and can choose our direction and thoughts, there are actually many invisible restrictions around us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, when a baby first comes into this world, it cannot walk, talk, or even crawl, and can only lie in the crib. In theory, it may try to crawl to the edge of the bed and try to crawl out, but that is extremely limited &amp;ldquo;freedom&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;start&#34;&gt;Start
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We could assume that consciousness &amp;ldquo;activates&amp;rdquo; at some point early in life. For some people, this may happen in the womb; for others, it may be after birth. For most people, consciousness is unstable at first, and it may enter and leave the body from time to time until it finally stabilizes and truly integrates into this reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we draw this process on a world line diagram, it is &amp;ldquo;falling into&amp;rdquo; the world line template map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0001.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1363&#34;
	height=&#34;761&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0001_hu_8efd12aa06260314.png 480w, https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0001_hu_8ca85334f150198c.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;179&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;429px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-first-few-minutes&#34;&gt;The first few minutes
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the first few minutes, days, and months, freedom of movement is very limited. The consciousness is still learning how to move, learning how to use the body. So the actual physical activity it can do is limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if it pushed itself, and it strove to overcome, it could roll, crawl, move and do other things that are very difficult to do. These difficult things can be defined as hills and mountains on the template map. Using the Z-axis, the higher the “mountain”, the harder the effort. The shallower the depression, the easier the effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0002.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1363&#34;
	height=&#34;761&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0002_hu_cad3c6bb49c6a618.png 480w, https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0002_hu_457afd3f890ccb0c.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;179&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;429px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time, consciousness moves on this template map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the personality of consciousness, it either chooses the easy route or it becomes a &amp;ldquo;tough guy&amp;rdquo; and pushes forward, striving to &amp;ldquo;climb those mountains.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can conclude that before birth, everyone corresponds to a preset &amp;ldquo;world line template&amp;rdquo;. This template largely determines the direction of your future development. Therefore, if you do nothing and live your life naturally, your future will be roughly predictable without much deviation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, if you decide to climb “those hills and mountains”, what then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0003.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1363&#34;
	height=&#34;761&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0003_hu_27cbe2eab511a4d6.png 480w, https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0003_hu_51a2652102ccc5c6.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;179&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;429px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;key-point&#34;&gt;Key Point
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The height of the &amp;ldquo;mountain&amp;rdquo; is a measure of effort and deviation from the comfortable norm of the consciousness&amp;rsquo;s pre-birth worldline template. When consciousness leaves the &amp;ldquo;flat, safe&amp;rdquo; median, it will change, but the change will not be great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is, the pre-birth worldline template will still remain pretty much the same. The consciousness will &amp;ldquo;climb that mountain&amp;rdquo; and then discover other areas that were originally forbidden to it, i.e., possibilities that were originally unreachable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the above inferences, it can be concluded that the location of entry into the template is very critical, which will determine how much effort the consciousness needs to put in to reach where they want to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;glossary&#34;&gt;Glossary
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;time&#34;&gt;Time
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the MWI, consciousness is constantly moving between worldlines, so what we call &amp;ldquo;time&amp;rdquo; is actually the experience and process of consciousness moving through the MWI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, each consciousness experiences their own version of &amp;ldquo;time&amp;rdquo;, which is determined by the speed at which the consciousness travels between worldlines. A &amp;ldquo;unified&amp;rdquo; time exists within a single worldline, but this is of no help to consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;life-line&#34;&gt;Life-Line
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;A “life-line” is a collection of experiences that a consciousness has. As the consciousness moves in and out of individual moments of time, it creates a path. This path looks like a vector. It starts at the moment of birth and ends at the moment of death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0004.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1196&#34;
	height=&#34;718&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0004_hu_be8d5b1c332eb89.png 480w, https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0004_hu_853d5c82b78c23c6.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;166&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;399px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;time-line&#34;&gt;Time-Line
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;A timeline is a segment of a lifeline. It can be a continuous segment of any lifeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0005.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1196&#34;
	height=&#34;733&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0005_hu_c596b3c3df77420a.png 480w, https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0005_hu_a0c7f9fb58aa1dba.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;163&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;391px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;world-line&#34;&gt;World-Line
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;A &amp;ldquo;world line&amp;rdquo; is a frozen moment, like a photograph. It contains its unique history and future. The history and future of each world line are different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as using the world-line map template, each intersection point, dot or globe represents one such world-line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0006.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1516&#34;
	height=&#34;871&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0006_hu_d3611a96c865e2b0.png 480w, https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0006_hu_c208612e39cf50b9.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;174&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;417px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;world-line-cluster&#34;&gt;World-Line Cluster
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the number of consciousnesses is finite, but the number of worldlines is close to infinite, then the probability that each consciousness has its own worldline is greatest. In other words, shared worldlines are rare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as the consciousness travels on the MWI it does so based upon it’s thoughts. If others share the same thoughts, they travel the MWI in a similar manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you map out the Time-Lines of people who are sharing similar thoughts, you will find that they seem to travel together, and they seem to experience the same World-lines. Which known as clustering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0007.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1182&#34;
	height=&#34;623&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0007_hu_a43582c4a123b58c.png 480w, https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0007_hu_7b66d6a9f805ca0c.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;189&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;455px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;echo-chamber&#34;&gt;Echo Chamber
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In discussions of news media, an echo chamber refers to situations in which beliefs are amplified or reinforced by communication and repetition inside a closed system and insulated from rebuttal. By participating in an echo chamber, people are able to seek out information that reinforces their existing views without encountering opposing views, potentially resulting in an unintended exercise in confirmation bias. Echo chambers may increase social and political polarization and extremism.
-Wikipedia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you only listen to a certain type of &amp;ldquo;news&amp;rdquo; and only receive opinions from others who agree with you, your thoughts will be reinforced into a set narrative and you will not be able to think other thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the perspective of MWI, it is dangerous to be in a closed environment where thoughts are set to &amp;ldquo;be in a rut&amp;rdquo;. It locks you into a path and drives you to a set place in MWI, whether good or bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;template-map&#34;&gt;Template Map
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The template map is a model used to visualize how consciousness moves in MWI. It can be thought of as a topological map, made up of grid intersections, each of which represents a &amp;ldquo;world line&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shape of the map surface reflects the most likely path a consciousness can move through its physical body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The height of the terrain represents the difficulty of movement. Flat areas symbolize easy movement without much effort, while &amp;ldquo;mountains&amp;rdquo; represent extremely high difficulties and challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0008.png&#34;
	width=&#34;841&#34;
	height=&#34;494&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0008_hu_ebc7767f550af72b.png 480w, https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0008_hu_c8ff8c3fc28e7a88.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;170&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;408px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;pre-birth-world-line-template-map&#34;&gt;Pre-Birth World-Line Template Map
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Refers to the first map that is set when a baby is born and the consciousness is injected into the body. This map is designed before the consciousness enters the material world, and its purpose is to allow the consciousness to experience a specific series of experiences in it. This is a carefully constructed specific life path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this map, the consciousness will travel along the most convenient path pre-set to experience a series of events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only way to leave this map is to &amp;ldquo;slide&amp;rdquo; into another completely different template map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;slide&#34;&gt;Slide
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;A slide is an intentional change of the template map. Consciousness “slide” off the map that you are on, and land on a completely different map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this can be accomplished through design, the most effective way (on an individual basis) is to do it through thinking. By specifically controlling your thoughts to slide out of the template map, sliding to the template that is next to it, like sliding from one layer of a layer cake to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0009.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1182&#34;
	height=&#34;1324&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0009_hu_b159eaf4cc414217.png 480w, https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0009_hu_c2adaf8a9e6921f8.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;89&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;214px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;shadow-people&#34;&gt;Shadow People
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consciousness travels through world lines alone. It is extremely rare for another consciousness to share a world line with us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for a consciousness, all these &amp;ldquo;people&amp;rdquo; it sees are actually just an empty container. They are real, and they have feelings that we react to, but its consciousness is not there, but on their own world line. This person on all other world lines is just a projection of the main consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;mountains&#34;&gt;Mountains
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the topography of a world-line template are “highs” and “lows”. These features define the difficulty of effort to move in those directions. A “mountain” is a particularly difficult are to traverse. And on the 3D map it will appear as a mountain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0010.png&#34;
	width=&#34;844&#34;
	height=&#34;499&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0010_hu_cf76851d46158d9.png 480w, https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0010_hu_92416cc9f069460f.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;169&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;405px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;hills&#34;&gt;Hills
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;A hill is similar to a mountain. It’s level of difficulty to traverse is proportionally smaller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0011.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1187&#34;
	height=&#34;691&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0011_hu_cc9b124234562f87.png 480w, https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0011_hu_a128211ac7286569.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;171&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;412px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;comfort-zone&#34;&gt;Comfort Zone
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;In actual experience, the flat, unruffled areas on the world line template map are the so-called &amp;ldquo;comfort zones&amp;rdquo;. No matter how rugged and steep the terrain ahead looks, there will always be a relatively smooth and easy path in the world line template set before birth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good thing is that no matter what you face in life, there is always a &amp;ldquo;default route&amp;rdquo; waiting for you to move forward; it may be smooth or difficult, but it always exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0012.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1187&#34;
	height=&#34;629&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0012_hu_758c0d01722ee856.png 480w, https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/0012_hu_ed3a7ce733eb4e9b.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;188&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;452px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Introduction and Index List</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/introduction-and-index-list/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/introduction-and-index-list/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;This document aims to systematically organize and summarize the core concepts related to the Many Worlds Interpretation (MWI) to help build a more complete understanding of the nature of reality. To facilitate thinking and communication, several simplified models and analogies are used in this document. These expressions strive to be close to reality, but they do not represent the only or final explanation. Please note: reality is far more complex than the model, and you should avoid construction as much as possible when reading this document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;index-list&#34;&gt;Index List
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;1.&lt;/code&gt; What is MWI - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/what-is-mwi/&#34; &gt;Introduction to MWI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
