<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Journal on Entropiex</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/tags/journal/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Journal on Entropiex</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Entropiex</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/tags/journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Cooperative Education</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/cooperative-education/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/cooperative-education/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/cooperative-education/ready-or-not-logo-squad-black-and-white.png" alt="Featured image of post Cooperative Education" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a fan of hardcore simulation games, I have dabbled in simulation games in various fields, including FPS games. However, as we can see, hardcore simulation FPS is very different from mainstream FPS, so I tend to divide all FPS into three types: hardcore, semi-simulation and entertainment. The first type of hardcore includes Arma, Squad, Ready or Not, Escape from Tarkov, Ground Branch and other works, and the second type of semi-simulation is Insurgency: Sandstorm, Battlefield, DayZ and so on. Entertainment is relatively broad, including Call of Duty, Apex Legends, Counter-Strike, Fortnite and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through the level of simulation, we can know the degree of &amp;ldquo;hardcore&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Dimension&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Judgment criteria&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Damage model/TTK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;One or two shots kill, no blood recovery; wound type segmentation&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ballistic physics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;There are drop, wind deflection, penetration, initial velocity, bullet type differences, etc.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operation complexity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Switch safety, pull bolt, manually load magazine, check ammunition&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modification freedom&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Generally high, including gun modification details and customized full body equipment&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interface/information&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;No HUD, no crosshairs, no radar&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tactical dependence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Strong reliance on teamwork, voice communication, tactical coordination&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Military communication, medical, supply, logistics system&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Map&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Huge map (strategic) or small map (tactical), always realistic&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Death penalty&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Zero cost or high cost&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relatively speaking, the more hardcore the game, the fewer players there are, and the higher the level required of the developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Death penalty, is a big difference between hardcore FPS games. Some of them (e.x. Tarkov) set up a extremely serious penalty, but some have almost no penalty (e.x. RoN).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now there is a interesting topic: Despite hardcore FPS is difficult, why do people still like to play it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, there are reasons for this. From a general perspective, it includes the following factors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;immersion&#34;&gt;Immersion
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether it is a visual work or a novel, immersion has always been an important evaluation dimension. Novels and visual works often use gorgeous pictures and texts to attract the audience, while hardcore FPS games go the opposite way, bringing an immersive feeling by simulating the real environment as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pursuit of realistic gameplay is also about the real environment. This will make the modeling and rendering effects of hardcore FPS much higher than those of mainstream FPS. The more realistic reflections and volumetric clouds/fog can sometimes be comparable to 3A works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;teamwork--communication&#34;&gt;Teamwork &amp;amp; Communication
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlike twitchy shooters where you can solo carry, hardcore FPS always demands cooperation. You can be John Wick, but it&amp;rsquo;s almost impossible. In Ready Or Not, solo CQB is extremely dangerous and no one would try or recommend it in real life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;skill-learning&#34;&gt;Skill Learning
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hardcore FPS rewards system for correct knowledge application, patience and discipline, not just quick reaction, not gun. Learning bullet trajectory, equipment management, tactical movements and communication cooperation management does not provide any rewards in itself, but by using these to successfully complete the mission, you will know what is useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;take-ready-or-not-as-an-example&#34;&gt;Take Ready or Not as an example
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hardcore FPS games often have RPG elements, and RoN is particularly good at this.
In RoN, a few bullets = death. One clean shot can end you, without health regen. You can get crippled, bleed out, or go down instantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes every action must meet the standard, and rushing out of the cover directly is asking for trouble. The game does not reward recklessness, nor does it deduct points for taking extra time. Caution is often the best, even if it takes more time. It is stressful, but it feels real. Surviving a mission with zero casualties feels rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In RoN, bullet penetration is real. Cover is not always safe. Your 9mm bullet will not penetrate wood like a 5.56. Walls can be full of holes and you may not know which hole a suspect is shooting from. If you don&amp;rsquo;t crouch down and hold your shield, your shield will shake and you will take damage. There is no sliding, jumping or even running here. In real life, no one wants the sound of running footsteps to alert the suspect to the arrival of SWAT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In RoN, there is no gear loss like in Tarkov, you get an F for failing a mission, and losing a teammate means a lower score. Unexpected deaths are stressful. It is the ultimate realization of &amp;ldquo;tactical fantasy&amp;rdquo;. Perfect coordination, precise point shooting, correct use of tactical weapons, clearing suspects without injury and completing the mission itself carries a sense of professionalism and coolness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Features&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Mainstream FPS&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Ready or Not&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Kill to win / Win the game&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Complete the mission / Rescue the hostages / Clear the target&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Death penalty&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Drop rank&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Mission failure&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Player behavior&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Reaction, luck, shooting&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Tactics, judgment, coordination&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Atmosphere&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Exciting but chaotic&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Calm, depressing, realistic&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI enemies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Stupid&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Relatively smart + deceptive &lt;br&gt;(fake surrender, attack from behind)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gameplay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Fast pace&lt;br&gt;restart after the game&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Slow pace&lt;br&gt;focus on process and details&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, the charm of RoN lies in that it forces you to restrain, learn, bear the consequences, learn the practices of real SWAT teams, understand the importance of cover, and truly learn CQB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game is not just a simulation of SWAT, but it trains players to become SWAT and understand the thinking of SWAT when performing tasks. Players start to find cover as much as possible, instead of &amp;ldquo;gunning&amp;rdquo; or blindly entering open areas, start to prioritize controlling the perspective, instead of blindly pushing the map, and learn how to let teammates cover themselves, instead of being a lone wolf hero. Skilled and realistic operations are accumulated through repeated officer downs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, the community environment of this type of tactical shooting/hardcore FPS games is more equal and friendly, there is generally no ranking system, everyone respects each other more, even if the skills are not good, they will only say that you are unprofessional. It is not like the mainstream FPS where the high rankings look down on the low ones and scold teammates for mistakes. In theory, the death penalty of the former is higher. Why can&amp;rsquo;t mainstream FPS players accept failure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, we can find that in hardcore FPS, death is often quick and fatal, but the game rhythm is slow, and cooperation is more important than individual performance. A mistake often leads to the failure of the entire team. Failure is serious, but also very natural. Players understand that anyone can be killed, not who is too bad. &amp;ldquo;Teamwork is more important than individual skills&amp;rdquo; is reflected here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In mainstream FPS, the fast-paced environment, leaderboards and quantitative indicators such as KDA are very prominent. Failure is seen as a lack of personal ability, and teammates are prone to accusing or dragging the team down. This is because in a battle, a highly skilled person can defeat others 1v10 through various &amp;ldquo;skills&amp;rdquo; and techniques. In this type of game, there are no Rules of Engagement, but Rules of Elimination. Recklessness is rewarded, and caution is punished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difference between the two communities is also huge. Hardcore FPS game communities are usually dominated by players who like military simulations and teamwork. They emphasize &amp;ldquo;respecting tactical processes&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;learning and communication&amp;rdquo;. Poor skills can also be seen as a need for practice, and the community is more inclined to guidance/discussion rather than malicious attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mainstream FPS community has a larger player base with varying levels of skill. Rankings and popularity make the competition more stressful, and players are more likely to be anxious or emotional. The language environment is more likely to become a battlefield because the game rhythm is intense and the emotions fluctuate greatly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Factors&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Tactical shooting games&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Mainstream FPS&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rhythm and failure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Slow pace, high cost of failure, team responsibility&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Fast pace, high pressure on individual performance&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community atmosphere&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Cooperation first&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Intense competition, obvious comparison&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ranking influence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;No or weak ranking, reduced comparison&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Kill quantification, high pressure on ranking&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Failure acceptance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Failure is a learning process&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Failure is seen as a lack of ability&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Player screening&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Like immersion and rigor&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Diversity, complex mentality&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;idealized-education-system&#34;&gt;Idealized Education System
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inspired by hardcore FPS, we found that increasing difficulty and removing competition will not repel players, but will make players actively learn and research, stimulating the motivation of independent learning. So how can we change the education system?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core concept is that students are not trained to &amp;ldquo;win the game&amp;rdquo; (grades), but to train like athletes. Not only pass, but also solve real problems and gain the ability to solve problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;first-step-exam-changes&#34;&gt;First step: Exam Changes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiple exams are allowed, multiple attempts are allowed, no time limit.&lt;/strong&gt;
In fact, the role of rankings is just to increase pressure, and the so-called positive effect is just to promote the superiority of those who rank high and to discourage those who rank low. This is why they need to be removed in the first place. A more open evaluation method can reduce the focus on grades and focus more on something truly valuable. The penalties for poor test scores should be weakened, and more time should be spent on reviewing and retrying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;second-step-more-teamwork&#34;&gt;Second step: More Teamwork
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All core learning tasks need to be completed through real collaboration.&lt;/strong&gt;
The difficulty and cost of completing the task by one person must be set very high. By encouraging real cooperation, rather than forcing tasks to be bound without any interests. The task must be in everyone&amp;rsquo;s interest and related to the interests of the group. Group members need to be randomly assigned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;third-step-pacing&#34;&gt;Third step: Pacing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-paced, independent time planning.&lt;/strong&gt;
Unlike a universal learning pace that is synchronized for all students, each individual&amp;rsquo;s pace should be different, the pace should be suitable for them, and they should not know each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fourth-step-minimal-guidance&#34;&gt;Fourth step: Minimal Guidance
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimal, limited, appropriate guidance.&lt;/strong&gt;
Minimal guidance and prompting and the removal of time limits allow students to learn to observe, analyze, and act early in their learning. The subsequent pace of learning can naturally accelerate, and students have very strong autonomous learning abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fifth-step-comprehensive-rating-feedback&#34;&gt;Fifth step: Comprehensive Rating Feedback
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debriefing, report, portfolios instead of rankings, class placement, GPA.&lt;/strong&gt;
The core of the evaluation should not be based on standardized test scores, but on actual results, works and discussions. Less passive memorization of instruction and more integration into project learning objectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-point-of-idealized-education-system&#34;&gt;Key Point of Idealized Education System
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;mission-based-curriculum--learning-through-immersion&#34;&gt;Mission-Based Curriculum &amp;amp; Learning through Immersion
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each subject has a clear target application scenario. The number of application questions should not be increased, but reduced and as few as possible with high quality. Project objectives should be exactly in line with the subject. They should not be designed to be too simple, as that would lose interest. Simple knowledge points should use simpler question formats, while project learning objectives should be more complex and often have no unified answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design and test a bridge with given constraints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Role-play policy advisors in historical turning points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;allow-slow-tactical-pacing&#34;&gt;Allow Slow, Tactical Pacing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You shouldn’t pursue speed in the early stages of learning, which is why time limits are removed. Not everyone learns at the same speed, so the time it takes for everyone to reach a certain point will also be different. Practice on the basis of excellent quality, and speed will also be improved on the basis of excellent quality. Quality always takes precedence over speed. The same is true in the market. There is no shortage of products, but there is a shortage of excellent products, and even more so, great products. Over time, good and fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage pauses for reflection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allows retrying of failed methods with better planning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Normalize debriefs after major assignments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;team-accountability&#34;&gt;Team Accountability
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Traditional classes are still too large organizations. Ideally, each group should not exceed 5 people, and individual achievements need to be balanced with collective achievements. Too large a collective organization will drown out individual achievements, and too small an organization is not conducive to the development of collaborative skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear roles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team success &amp;gt; individual brilliance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built-in peer review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;natural-punishment-and-reward&#34;&gt;Natural Punishment and Reward
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Grades replaced or supported by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planning and assigning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Task completion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Requirement achievement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post-mission reports &amp;amp; Reflections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;respect-based-community&#34;&gt;Respect-Based Community
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In RoN, failure is expected, and support is constructive. Facts have also proved that positive thoughts are always more conducive to learning and progress than negative emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove rigid ranking systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emphasize shared growth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use feedback instead of shame&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replace “gifted vs. average” with “trained vs. untrained”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To sum up the above, we find that the high difficulty represented by hardcore FPS games is not disgusting. We can improve the learning environment that is also considered to be difficult in the same way, thereby improving our perception and enthusiasm for learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage deep, experiential learning over fast test-taking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cultivate teamwork and communication as a central skill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Embrace failure as tactical feedback, not personal inadequacy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality always over speed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treat students as person in training, not score chasers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make learning immersive, strategic, and professionally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Boring MBTI System</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/the-boring-mbti-system/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/the-boring-mbti-system/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought it would be helpful to describe how my attitude towards MBTI has changed over the past few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the MBTI framework offers a compelling way to understand personality patterns, it ultimately simplifies the complexity of human behavior into static categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are dynamic, and their thoughts, actions, and motivations often shift with context, age, and experience. There are also huge differences between people in their ability and degree to control their thoughts. Therefore the binary system created by MBTI is an extremely simplified system that is easy to understand but is not true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we must take into account the complexity of the system and try to conduct research in a more fitting way. Classification will inevitably lead to bias, and this bias in the MBTI system has the probability of stereotyping people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The limitations of the MBTI are already quite obvious, and it is clear that it constrains many people, both in terms of behavior and potential. I tend to believe that individuals are unique and special, and trying to describe all individuals using 16 types is a very simplified and easy to understand way, which is what makes it so popular, but it does not represent its accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People always want something to be fixed, but reality is often dynamic. It is understandable that seeking to fix reality is a lazy behavior, and this is also true for psychological research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a good example of individual peculiarity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>INTJ: Born Achiever and Loser</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/intj-born-achiever-and-loser/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/intj-born-achiever-and-loser/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;pathway-of-an-intj&#34;&gt;Pathway of an INTJ
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;lower-stage&#34;&gt;Lower stage
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the lower stage, the INTJ usually presents as a being weaker than ordinary people. They have extraordinary self-confidence and arrogance, look down on everything, are introverted, like to think about problems but often dare not really be independent, their grades cannot crush their classmates, they have not carried out large-scale learning and self-discipline, and their thoughts are not objective, materialistic, and practical. They have no ability to counteract these huge side effects of being an INTJ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;transition-l-m&#34;&gt;Transition L-M
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After experiencing a mental transformation (usually a breakdown and remodeling) caused by long-term thinking, they realize that arrogance and coldness are not conducive to achieving their goals, so they try to become more humble and use personality masks. As they gradually have a concept of their goals and the path in between, INTJs at this stage will improve their ability to act and their thirst for knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;middle-stage&#34;&gt;Middle stage
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A middle stage INTJ possesses high intelligence, deep philosophical thinking, and strong self-discipline. They can analyze most things clearly and independently resolve various peculiar thoughts. Having dedicated thousands or even tens of thousands of hours to learning, they have developed exceptional decision-making, judgment, and perception through extensive reading, far surpassing the accuracy of ordinary individuals. Their academic performance and achievements exceed those of most peers. Becoming more social and communicative, fearless in standing out, and establish rules and order for their teams. Able to control time and energy in certain extent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;transition-m-h&#34;&gt;Transition M-H
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This stage has approached or achieved success in a secular sense, and after several years of development, has made outstanding contributions or achievements in a specific field. Gradually, they have acquired high-level rationality and the ability to predict the times, breaking free from the limitations of emotional and physical basic feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;higher-stage&#34;&gt;Higher stage
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Higher stage INTJs are built on top rationality, understand the laws of the world, have accurate long-term prediction capabilities, learning abilities, and terrifying execution capabilities. High stage INTJs are only limited by their physical and time limits, so they usually reach the pinnacle in a field, can thoroughly study the things they love and influence others, can soar to the sky in good times, and can turn the tide in bad times. They dare to be unique and are not afraid of power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;置之死地而后生&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;置之死地而后生&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;People like and admire INTJs, but only high-level INTJs. Their decisiveness, perseverance, and courage are highly praised, and their near-absolute rationality is called a miracle. However, the more perfect these abilities are, the deeper the gap between the middle and high levels is. The M-H stage will be a hurdle that most people will never be able to cross in their lifetime, and it is also the stage that only a few top entrepreneurs, politicians, and financial tycoons can overcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INTJ&amp;rsquo;s aversion to stupidity and their own arrogance make them more accepted by society the higher they are. For lower- and middle-stage INTJs, accepting the reality of being weak, being open-minded and objective, studying as diligently as possible, and always being optimistic are the only ways to reach a higher level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;interesting-vs-meaningful&#34;&gt;Interesting vs. Meaningful
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;external-rules-and-influences&#34;&gt;External rules and influences
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;INTJ&amp;rsquo;s instinct is to pursue efficiency. If they don&amp;rsquo;t see the meaning of something, they won&amp;rsquo;t even take a second look at it in order to &amp;ldquo;maximize efficiency.&amp;rdquo; However, what many people think of as &amp;ldquo;meaningful&amp;rdquo; is actually based on external rules, such as getting into a good school, finding a good job, and winning social recognition. These are value systems defined by others, and are &amp;ldquo;finite games&amp;rdquo; that will eventually fall into endless competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;finite-games-vs-infinite-games&#34;&gt;Finite games vs. infinite games
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The goal of a finite game is to win, so the rules are clear and there are many competitors, leading to involution. The goal of an infinite game is to continue and explore, and the rules can be created, so the competitive pressure is much smaller. INTJs have the advantages of systematic thinking and strategic planning, and can completely choose not to get involved in the established track, but to establish their own game rules, enter the “wilderness”, and open up their own path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;find-something-that-is-truly-interesting&#34;&gt;Find something that is truly “interesting”
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;INTJs tend to execute efficiently, but their thinking framework is often driven by external goals, which easily leads to them just optimizing the existing system and ignoring the possibility of creating a new system. To find something “interesting”, the key is to slow down, return to life, and observe which things can make you invest in it for a long time even without external rewards. In other words, if something doesn&amp;rsquo;t need external recognition and you&amp;rsquo;re still willing to work on it, then it may be worth pursuing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-value-of-time&#34;&gt;The value of time
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For INTJs, time is the most valuable resource. The real strategy is not to fight for a tiny advantage in a highly competitive race, but to find areas that have not yet been noticed by the mainstream, set your own rules there, and become a rule maker rather than a passive player in the game. This not only improves the return on investment (ROI), but also conforms to INTJ&amp;rsquo;s long-term planning mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;supplement&#34;&gt;Supplement
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In business, breadth is a cost, and depth is a profit. For INTJs, the requirements are even more stringent. They must be both generalists and experts, understand all walks of life, and be the best in their own profession. This puts a double test on time and body, which is one of the reasons why top successful people are so rare.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>ASI 2030</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/asi-2030/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/asi-2030/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/asi-2030/RSI-NewBabbage.png" alt="Featured image of post ASI 2030" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is an interesting speculation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If AGI/ASI is truly one of the biggest changes in human history, then it’s important to know the worst-case scenario. If they do come to pass, it will be a darker future than Cyberpunk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;technology-evolution-timeline&#34;&gt;Technology Evolution Timeline
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2025-2030&lt;/strong&gt;: AGI emerges, leading to the large-scale replacement of standardized intellectual work. Humans retain only symbolic decision-making power.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2031-2035&lt;/strong&gt;: ASI achieves breakthroughs, taking over strategic decision-making. Corporate CEOs become mere &amp;ldquo;AI interpreters.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2036-2045&lt;/strong&gt;: Human-machine integration becomes essential for survival. Those without neural implants are marginalized. Consciousness uploading becomes the new class divide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;social-stratification&#34;&gt;Social Stratification
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruling Class (0.01%)&lt;/strong&gt;: Controls computing power, engages in genetic optimization, and profits from time differentials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Class (9.99%)&lt;/strong&gt;: Maintains human-machine interactions, optimizes data value, and exploits AI vulnerabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disposable Class (90%)&lt;/strong&gt;: Provides data, virtual labor, or serves as &amp;ldquo;biological containers&amp;rdquo; for consciousness uploads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;control-over-key-resources&#34;&gt;Control Over Key Resources
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computing power is monopolized by oligarchs, capable of instantly wiping out dissenters&amp;rsquo; assets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data becomes the new form of enslavement—ordinary individuals generate data but cannot profit from it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time is commodified—the wealthy can store their consciousness, while the poor must sign &amp;ldquo;time debt&amp;rdquo; contracts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-prediction&#34;&gt;Final Prediction
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;By &lt;strong&gt;2045&lt;/strong&gt;, AI computing power surpasses the singularity threshold. Decisions made before 2030 will determine the survival conditions of 2045.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This will be a highly algorithm-driven and computationally dominated future, where social stratification will be even more extreme than it is today. Energy, biotechnology, and AI will all develop rapidly, and the living space of ordinary people will be greatly compressed. From an individual perspective, the only way out is to act quickly and strive for a proactive position before the ASI era arrives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously a lot of things need to be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Occam&#39;s Razor and Bayesianism</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/occams-razor-and-bayesianism/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/occams-razor-and-bayesianism/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In simple models and complex models, as long as the simple model is consistent with the results, its confidence is much higher than that of the complex model. When this gap is infinitely magnified by multiple parameters, from the perspective of Bayesian probability, the simple model is either directly rejected, but as long as it can roughly match the experimental data, it is better than the complex model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This includes 2 parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;occams-razor-and-bayesianism&#34;&gt;Occam&amp;rsquo;s Razor and Bayesianism
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Occam&amp;rsquo;s Razor&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Bayesianism&lt;/strong&gt; are two important principles in reasoning and scientific philosophy. Occam’s Razor emphasizes &lt;strong&gt;simplicity&lt;/strong&gt;, favoring explanations that introduce the fewest unnecessary assumptions. Bayesianism, on the other hand, focuses on probabilistic reasoning, continuously updating our beliefs based on new evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;occams-razor-favoring-simpler-explanations&#34;&gt;Occam’s Razor: Favoring Simpler Explanations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Occam’s Razor states that &lt;strong&gt;when multiple explanations exist, the simplest one is usually the best&lt;/strong&gt;. This idea was introduced by the 14th-century philosopher &lt;strong&gt;William of Ockham&lt;/strong&gt;, who argued that we should avoid unnecessary complexity in our reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if a strange noise is heard at night, one could assume either:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was caused by the wind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was caused by ghosts moving objects around the house.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occam’s Razor suggests choosing the first explanation because it relies on well-understood natural causes rather than introducing additional, unproven assumptions. While simplicity alone does not guarantee correctness, it often leads to more practical and testable theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bayesianism-updating-beliefs-based-on-evidence&#34;&gt;Bayesianism: Updating Beliefs Based on Evidence
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bayesianism is a way of reasoning that helps us refine our beliefs as we gather more information. Instead of treating ideas as either absolutely true or false, it considers different possibilities and adjusts how likely each one is based on new evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, if a doctor suspects a patient has a certain illness, they do not immediately confirm it. Instead, they look at symptoms, test results, and medical history, gradually becoming more confident in a diagnosis as more information is gathered.&lt;br&gt;
If new evidence contradicts the initial assumption, the doctor revises their belief and considers other possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method is widely used in fields such as science, machine learning, and even everyday decision-making. It allows us to make better predictions and avoid jumping to conclusions too quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-relationship-between-o-and-b&#34;&gt;The Relationship Between O. and B.
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More complex explanations usually have lower initial credibility.&lt;/strong&gt; When we lack strong evidence, it makes sense to assume simpler explanations are more likely, aligning with Occam’s Razor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bayesian reasoning naturally favors simpler theories unless the evidence strongly supports a more complex one.&lt;/strong&gt; If two explanations fit the data equally well, the simpler one is usually more likely to be correct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>World Trends and Crisis Study</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/world-trends-and-crisis-study/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/world-trends-and-crisis-study/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been looking for the future direction recently, so I studied the development of the past few decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 1950 to 2025, a significant economic crisis or major economic adjustment occurs approximately every 10 years. During this period, the global economy has undergone an evolution from post-war reconstruction, technological innovation, market-oriented reforms to informatization and globalization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-1950s-postwar-reconstruction-and-economic-prosperity&#34;&gt;1. 1950s: Postwar reconstruction and economic prosperity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the end of World War II, the world entered a period of post-war reconstruction. The economies of Western Europe and Japan recovered rapidly, and the United States became the global economic leader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-1960s-technological-innovation-and-social-change&#34;&gt;2. 1960s: Technological innovation and social change
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Technological advances (such as computers and aerospace) and social movements (such as the civil rights movement and the counterculture) flourished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-1970s-oil-crisis-and-economic-stagflation&#34;&gt;3. 1970s: Oil crisis and economic stagflation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) imposed an oil embargo, causing oil prices to soar and triggering global economic stagflation (high inflation and high unemployment coexisting). Two oil shocks in 1973 and 1979 led to a slowdown in global economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-1980s-market-oriented-reforms-and-globalization&#34;&gt;4. 1980s: Market-oriented reforms and globalization
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many countries have implemented market-oriented reforms and liberalization policies, and the process of globalization has accelerated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-1990s-information-technology-revolution-and-economic-prosperity&#34;&gt;5. 1990s: Information technology revolution and economic prosperity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The information technology (IT) revolution has driven global economic growth, and the Internet and digital transformation have become mainstream. The Asian financial crisis in 1997 had an impact on emerging market countries, but the global economy generally maintained growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-2000s-global-financial-crisis-and-economic-adjustment&#34;&gt;6. 2000s: Global financial crisis and economic adjustment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;IT exploded in developing countries, and the global financial market became highly integrated. The Internet winter in 2001 and the global financial crisis in 2008 led to a global economic recession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;7-2010s-post-crisis-era-and-the-rise-of-emerging-markets&#34;&gt;7. 2010s: Post-crisis era and the rise of emerging markets
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Countries implemented stimulus policies, and the global economy gradually recovered. Emerging market countries such as China rose&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;8-2020s-pandemic-and-economic-reconstruction&#34;&gt;8. 2020s: Pandemic and economic reconstruction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic triggered a global health crisis, giving rise to remote work and digital transformation. In 2020, the global economy contracted significantly due to the pandemic, and countries subsequently implemented stimulus policies to promote recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Future</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/future/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/future/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s January again! Happy new year to you all guys!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s electronic products are thinner and lighter than before, but they are still very heavy, especially those laptops with good performance that weigh more than one kilogram. Today’s quantum computers are larger and heavier than traditional computers—they are housed in specific rooms and run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This prompts us to ask: what kinds of products could define the future? Can we experience the same level of excitement as we did with groundbreaking releases like the MacBook or the iPhone X?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One promising candidate is AR glasses powered by directional beam charging technology. Currently, most AR glasses fail to replace smartphones, primarily due to their weight, with bulky batteries being the main culprit. Since this, if we can cancel the battery and use a power bank to charge, also replace the wire to wireless RF (radio frequency) technology, such as millimeter-wave directional transmission, all above problems will be solved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest challenges are: heating problem, high energy consumption ratio chip and High-resolution transparent display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same technology has the potential to revolutionize aerospace. Traditional space elevators are constrained by material limitations. By eliminating these materials and instead using ion thrusters with vector control to maintain a fixed orbit, coupled with wireless RF technology for power transmission, we could bypass these constraints entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would pave the way for a low-Earth orbit transportation method far more efficient than traditional rockets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future of technology is brimming with possibilities, although we feel like the technological progress has gradually slowed down or even stalled, but in fact there are still many conceptual technologies that have not been widely used.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Journal 1</title>
        <link>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/journal-1/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://enthalpiex.github.io/en/p/journal-1/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Per Aspera Ad Astra, which refers &amp;ldquo;Through suffering to the stars&amp;rdquo;. The specific object of suffering here is still a mystery to me, but it may be a little clearer now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite Chinese translation of this sentence is &amp;ldquo;历尽艰辛，终抵群星&amp;rdquo; (After going through all the hardships, one will finally reach the stars). The brilliance of the second half is easy to understand, but the first half is too vague. What is suffering refers to? Make the right choice at the right time, sacrifice the minor to save the major in critical moment, doing things that are useful but painful, or trying to force progress when motivation is weak?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isolate pain may be a great method to avoid it influence the motivation and energy, but what’s interesting is that the isolation method itself also consumes energy. Is this a loss-making exercise or a way to save the greater good?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, I believe that the final answer will be complex, because of this complicated world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
